Most of us in the entrepreneurial community are blessed—or cursed—with higher-than-average ambition.
我们创业圈里的大多数人都有幸——或者说不幸——拥有高于平均水平的雄心。
Ambitious people strongly desire accomplishments and are willing to take more risks and spend more effort to get them.
雄心勃勃的人强烈渴望取得成就，也愿意为此承担更多风险、付出更多努力。
Overall, this is a positive quality, especially for people trying to build their own businesses.
总体而言，这是一种积极的品质，对那些努力创办自己企业的人来说尤其如此。
Apparently, if you’re more naturally driven to set goals, you are more likely to succeed.
看起来，如果你天生更有动力去设定目标，你就更有可能成功。
Actually, this isn’t always the case.
实际上，情况并非总是如此。
In fact, in some cases, extreme ambition may end up doing more harm than good.
事实上，在某些情况下，极度的雄心最终可能弊大于利。
One major side effect of excessive ambition is the tendency to focus too determinedly on one particular vision or end goal.
过度的雄心有一个主要的副作用，就是容易让人过于固执地专注于某一个特定的愿景或最终目标。
This is problematic because it hinders your ability to adapt to new circumstances, which is vital if you want to be a successful entrepreneur.
这之所以成问题，是因为它会妨碍你适应新情况的能力，而如果你想成为一名成功的创业者，这种能力至关重要。
If a new competitor emerges to threaten your business, you may need to change direction, even if that means straying from your original vision.
如果有新的竞争对手出现，威胁到你的企业，你可能就需要改变方向，即使这意味着偏离你最初的愿景。
If you have too much ambition, you’ll find this hard, if not impossible.
如果你的雄心太大，你会发现这即使并非不可能，也很难做到。
Few people are successful when they try to build their first brand.
很少有人在尝试打造自己的第一个品牌时就取得成功。
Unfortunately, for the most ambitious entrepreneurs, a failure is seen as disastrous, and impossible to recover from.
遗憾的是，在最有雄心的创业者看来，失败是灾难性的，不可能从中恢复过来。
It’s a clear departure from the intended plan toward the intended goal.
失败就是明显偏离了通向既定目标的既定计划。
For people with limited ambition, however, failure is viewed as something closer to reality.
然而，在雄心有限的人看来，失败是一件更贴近现实的事。
Remember, failure is inevitable, and every failure you survive is a learning experience.
记住，失败是不可避免的，而你挺过的每一次失败，都是一次学习的经历。
Ambitious people tend to be more materially successful than their non-ambitious counterparts.
与没有雄心的人相比，雄心勃勃的人在物质上往往更成功。
However, they’re only slightly happier than their less-ambitious counterparts, and tend to live significantly shorter lives.
然而，他们只比雄心较小的人稍微快乐一点，而且寿命往往明显更短。
This implies that even though ambitious people are more likely to achieve conventional “success,” such success means nothing for their health and happiness—and if you don’t have health and happiness, what else could possibly matter?
这表明，尽管雄心勃勃的人更有可能取得传统意义上的“成功”，但这种成功对他们的健康和幸福毫无意义——而如果你没有健康和幸福，其他的又怎么可能重要呢？
Clearly, some amount of ambition is good for your motivation.
显然，一定程度的雄心对你的积极性有好处。
Without any ambition, you wouldn’t start your own business, set or achieve goals, or get far in life.
如果没有一点雄心，你就不会创办自己的企业，不会设定或实现目标，在人生道路上也走不远。
But an excess of ambition can also be dangerous, putting you at risk of burnout, stubbornness and even a shorter life.
但雄心过度也可能很危险，会让你面临倦怠、固执甚至寿命缩短的风险。